<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Streamliners</title>
    <link>https://thestreamliners.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Streamliners</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thestreamliners.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JU eezy</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/ju-eezy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 18:07:16 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/ju-eezy/</guid>
      <description>Problems solved Following are the features of the JU eezy app :
Homepage that looks promisingEveryday help available at your fingertips Campus GuideView entire floor map of any building Search across the campusYou can easily search indoor location of any classroom, lab, office etc. Search by Faculty&amp;#39;s nameGet faculty cabin&amp;#39;s location by searching with faculty&amp;#39;s name Room descriptionView alternate names, faculty details etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LocatIN</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/locatin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/locatin/</guid>
      <description>What we do? We solve the problem of building fast, lightweight and easy to use indoor map solution for large infrastructures.
We are eagerly looking for customers. If you want your venue to be digitalized, contact us now! We will build a Unique NextGen Indoor map solution for your campus.
We are an incubated start-up @ JECRC Incubation center, JECRC University.
 
Videos  Introductory video      LocatIN for university      Big Picture</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karobar Easy</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/karobar-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/karobar-easy/</guid>
      <description>  Major features of the app         document.addEventListener( &#39;DOMContentLoaded&#39;, function () {new Splide( &#39;#slider3&#39; , {padding : 0, type : &#34;loop&#34;, rewind : true, lazyLoad: &#39;nearby&#39;}).mount();} );  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Byaaz Book</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/byaaz-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/byaaz-book/</guid>
      <description>Major features of the app are : Interest CalculatorYou can calculate the interest in two different ways i.e. Simple Interest and Compound interest, based on your preference. Backup &amp;amp; RestoreYou can backup your whole data of customers and their transactions, with just one click. Byaaj Book gives you the flexibility to restore the whole content of the app. Fully DynamicYou can edit the customers, bills, and transactions, by long tapping on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ambika Parts</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/ambika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/ambika/</guid>
      <description>Ambika Parts consists of 2 apps, one for users and one for Admin.
User app Following are the major features of the user app :
Slideshow on Main pageUsing slideshow, admin can notiy his users of Main service or Information/Notice that he wants to deliver Shop Status &amp;amp; TimingUsers can check whether the shop is closed or open and how much time is left to open/close Lottery SystemTo increase user Engagement this app provides weekly Lottery Lottery SystemUsers get notified of new lottery Coin systemTo increase sales, this app provides virtual coins on offline shopping which indeed gives prize Showcase GalleryThis feature helps owner to show important items to their users document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VFresh</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/vfresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/vfresh/</guid>
      <description>Demo Following is a video walk-through of the VFresh eCom Platform :
  You can try out the app here.
Admin app Features of Admin app :
PowerfulAdmin app provides all the powers in a single app Manage CategoriesAdmin can organize item in categories. Categories are fully dynamic and can be edited anytime, anywhere. Sub categoriesWithin a category, there can be any number of sub categories Product ManagementAdmin can manage products within the app Add/Edit productAdmin can add/edit products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Gaya</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/smart-gaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/smart-gaya/</guid>
      <description>This video shows how the app functions:
  
User app Following are the major features of the user app :
All service at your fingertipsYou can order any service you want, from salon, carpenter, AC Services, WiFi provider, Painters, Tutor, RO service, Plumber, CCTV, Driver, Accounts and many more Gaya TourIt helps users find cool and chilling Place from temples to bars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Bazaar</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/food-bazaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/food-bazaar/</guid>
      <description>Shopkeeper app Features of Shopkeeper app :
DynamicShopkeeper can edit menu, working hours, promocodes etc. anytime Order managementShopkeeper can manage orders and filter them by date document.addEventListener( &#39;DOMContentLoaded&#39;, function () {new Splide( &#39;#slider1&#39; , {padding : 0, type : &#34;loop&#34;, rewind : true, lazyLoad: &#39;nearby&#39;}).mount();} ); User app Features of User app :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blushed</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/blushed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/blushed/</guid>
      <description>This was a project we developed from scratch during an internship. The app UI has evolved after that. But still the core logic is written by us. The new app looks as follows.
Features Top StoriesView the latest and popular stories on top CategriesBrowse through various categories Dark ModeRead in bed without hurting your eyes FilterFilter stories based on language you prefer AutoplayMessages can be shown in an hands-free autoplay mode Unique options panelFrom options, one can toggle sound effects, read description of story or delete progress Likes &amp;amp; BookmarksLike &amp;amp; bookmark your favourite stories GuideThe app helps you understand the UI/UX Track progressEasily see how much you&amp;#39;ve read Shimmer effectBeautiful Shimmer animation for loading data Swipe to removeEasily remove stories from Bookmarks, Likes by swiping document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE Crucial Pillars</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-crucial-pillars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-crucial-pillars/</guid>
      <description>CSE Crucial Pillars Hi Everyone,
I got an opportunity to speak and share my thoughts and experience on Computer Science whole as a Roadmap to my Juniors.
When this invitation arrived.. I was in a dilemma of :- How to Summarise CS as a whole in a deliverable of 15-20 mins..
Here’s what I summarised for the Building minds: Computer Science Engineering Journey can be presented to everyone in 3 important and key pillars :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using startActivityForResult Intent Launchers in Compose</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/using-intentlaunchers-in-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/using-intentlaunchers-in-compose/</guid>
      <description>Namaskaram!
Problem Android provides the following intent launcher APIs:
  Legacy, Deprecated : startActivityForResult() &amp;amp; onActivityResult()
  New: registerForActivityResult()
  Both APIs are tightly coupled with Activity as they are functions of Activity.
Launching such intents from composables is tricky because of 2 reasons:
  Passing launcher instance to Composable : registerForActivityResult() returns an instance of ActivityResultLauncher. To launch, this instance is required ( like launcher.launch(intent) ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalability Challenge in Karobar Easy</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/scalability-challenge-in-karobar-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/scalability-challenge-in-karobar-easy/</guid>
      <description>Namaskaram,
The recent growth in Karobar Easy users made the attendanceUpdater Cloud Function fail! This failure caused inconsistency in the database several times. It took 2 rewrites of the entire cloud function to finally fix the issue. This has been a challenging yet interesting journey for me. So, here I am sharing the incident with you all.
The attendanceUpdater Cloud Function (ClFn) runs at midnight everyday. It has the following responsibilities :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notification Broadcast using BitVector</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/notification-broadcast-using-bitvector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/notification-broadcast-using-bitvector/</guid>
      <description>Namaskaram,
In this blog, I will be sharing an amazing story where I used BitVector &amp;amp; Bitwise operators to save myself from writing complex code &amp;amp; also using up a lot of Server Bandwidth.
The problem During my journey as an Android Developer, I came across a use case where I needed to send personalized notifications to my users.
This app was JU eezy, which I developed for our University. I had to send notifications to users based on their profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revoke role access using Firestore Security rules</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/revoke-role-access-using-firestore-security-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/revoke-role-access-using-firestore-security-rules/</guid>
      <description>Namaskaram,
Many applications require Role Based access. For example : in an e-commerce project, roles like Admin, Shopkeeper, Agent etc. may exist. Granting and revoking the access manually can be hard &amp;amp; inefficient.
In this blog, I am sharing an easy &amp;amp; efficient way to grant &amp;amp; revoke role based access in a Firebase app.
Naive approach   Let&amp;rsquo;s say : you have an Admin app where only authorised Admins should be able to login &amp;amp; access the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating custom notifications</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/creating-custom-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/creating-custom-notifications/</guid>
      <description>Notifications alert you to many things on your Android device, including incoming messages, new emails, and calendar events. Notifications work slightly differently for each app, but they&amp;rsquo;re easy to customize.
Starting in Android 8.0 (API level 26), all notifications must be assigned to a channel. For each channel, you can set the visual and auditory behavior that is applied to all notifications in that channel. Then, users can change these settings and decide which notification channels from your app should be intrusive or visible at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement Location Picker like Ola and Uber in Android Effortlessly</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/location-picker-like-ola-and-uber-in-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/location-picker-like-ola-and-uber-in-android/</guid>
      <description>We all come across applications or ideas where we may want users to pick or select their location from maps. From a UX perspective, it is more convenient to pick a location than to manually enter the fields given.
Also, from the developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective getting user location with pinpoint accuracy helps in getting the job done as required concerning location more precisely.
So, how to implement it? Well, it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy, you just have to call a few Google Maps APIs, set up location permissions precisely, and create your layout for location picker and that’s all!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebase Log Events</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/firebase-log-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/firebase-log-events/</guid>
      <description>Firebase provides very powerful feature which is “Log Events”. The power of this feature is that you can check which feature of your app is used mostly by the users.
Let’s deep dive into the implementation (note that the complete implementation is in Java)
Add this library in your build.gradle file:
implementation &amp;#39;com.google.firebase:firebase-analytics&amp;#39; I had used firebase bom in my project so their is no need to give version to firebase-analytics library</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement RecyclerView in android with kotlin</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/recycler-view-with-kotlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/recycler-view-with-kotlin/</guid>
      <description>Do you have a large list of data to show to the users of your application?
Want a flexible and developer and user friendly way to show the data?
Then RecyclerView is the right choice.
RecyclerView is an advanced version of ListView that is more powerful and flexible.
It is a ViewGroup which is the successor of ListView and GridView including improvement on both of them.
As the name suggests, RecyclerView recycle the views which are out of visibility of user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing Android Code</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/organized-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/organized-code/</guid>
      <description>Tips to keep your android project files and code organized Overview Android applications should always be neatly organized with a clear folder structure that makes your code easy to read. In addition, proper naming conventions for code and classes are important to ensure your code is clean and maintainable.
The importance of an organized code structure It&amp;rsquo;s all about readability. Big projects can be difficult to organize due to the amount of classes, resource files and libraries used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Alarm manager</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/implement-alarm-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/implement-alarm-manager/</guid>
      <description>How to implement an alarm in your android application using AlarmManager?  Android AlarmManager allows you to access system alarm.
With the help of AlarmManager in android, you can schedule your application to run at a specific time in the future.
AlarmManager is a bridge between application and Android system alarm service. It can send a broadcast to your app (which can be completely terminated by user) at a scheduled time and your app can then perform any task accordingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebase Push notifications using Admin SDK</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/firebase-push-notifications-in-android-using-admin-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/firebase-push-notifications-in-android-using-admin-sdk/</guid>
      <description>How to send push notifications through an Android app using firebase?  A notification is a message you can display to the user outside of your application’s normal UI. When you tell the system to issue a notification, it first appears as an icon in the notification area. Notifications are important to give timely updates to your android app users they require minimal UI to notify the user about the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Markdown Essentials</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/mastering-markdown-essentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/mastering-markdown-essentials/</guid>
      <description>A language to write across web platforms.  It is a lightweight markup language for creating formatted text using a plain text editor, and also allows HTML components for styling texts.
It is easy-to-use syntax for styling all forms of writing and widely used in blogging, instant messaging, online forums, collaborative software, documentation pages and readme files on Github and various other platforms.
We can control the display of the document; formatting words as bold or italic, adding images, and creating lists are just a few of the things we can do in markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background Location Permission in Android 11 and above</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/background-location-permission-in-android-11-and-above/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/background-location-permission-in-android-11-and-above/</guid>
      <description>Request background location permission in all android versions using Java With lastest android version Android 11, some security is added for location. Now to access background location, users have to manually “Allow all the time” in settings.
For using foreground and background location in lower versions of Android 11, we can take permission ACCESS_FINE_LOCATION, this permission will be considered for both foreground and background but with Android 11 and above you have to take one more permission ACCESS_BACKGROUND_LOCATION separately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Custom Toast in Android</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/designing-custom-toast-in-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/designing-custom-toast-in-android/</guid>
      <description>We all love to add toast in places we want to check something, check on click events, give some short messages to user they have endless use. But putting a same toast for different kind of messages such as success, error, alert can be confusing and may not be visually alarming to users.
So what is the solution? We can design custom views and then inflate them in Toast. Below are some kind of examples we will be implementing, to create our custom Toast which will look cool and visually satisfying to users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement Notification Count overlay inside Android App</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/implement-notification-count-overlay-inside-android-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/implement-notification-count-overlay-inside-android-app/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to add notification count or badge like this to your app? Well everyone developer wants to add it as it improves User Experience significantly.
Its always handy to know how many notification I have when I open my app.
For the demo purpose we shall be creating this layout.
 Step 1 Add this custom UI implementation to app-level gradle file. We will be using this library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a Offline QR Generation and Scanning in Android</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/implement-a-offline-qr-generation-and-scanning-in-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/implement-a-offline-qr-generation-and-scanning-in-android/</guid>
      <description>QR Code scanner or Barcode scanner for android features are present in many apps to read some useful data.
Barcodes can scan things ranging from URL, Contact info to Geolocation, WIFI, Driver license IDs.
QR Code is the more popular format and is commonly seen in many applications from digital payments, automating production, enabling attendance for employees for a business and many more.
Below, we’ll be developing an application that scans the QR Code value from a bitmap image as well as detects QR Code through a camera and perform the relevant actions, without need of a internet connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design a Custom Phone Authentication with Firebase for Android</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/design-a-custom-phone-authentication-with-firebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/design-a-custom-phone-authentication-with-firebase/</guid>
      <description>Many apps require their users to be authenticated. So for the purpose of authenticating the apps uses phone number authentication inside their apps.
When you use phone number authentication, you have many benefits like
 Preventing Fake Users: When you use phone authentication, the user can’t be able to register for multiple accounts, as for each account a unique phone number is needed. Increase User Value: When you have all the users verified by a phone number the value of your user base increases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localize your Android App with multiple language options</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/localize-your-android-app-with-multiple-language-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/localize-your-android-app-with-multiple-language-options/</guid>
      <description>Android runs on many devices in many regions. To reach the most users, your app should handle text, audio files, numbers, currency, and graphics in ways appropriate to the locales where your app is used.
It is not enough to use only one languageoption while developing applications. When we publish our applications, there may be users who want to use it in different languages or who do not know the languagewe have developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Biometric Authentication in Java Android</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/implementing-biometric-authentication-in-java-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/implementing-biometric-authentication-in-java-android/</guid>
      <description>Thinking of adding your own app lock to your android app? Adding a biometric app lock 🔒 to protect your user from unauthorized usage, protect their data and information can be really helpful.
Biometric authentication allows you to quickly unlock your device with your fingerprint or face, confirming it’s really you who’s using the app.
Android’s biometric APIs allow for secure authentication on the Android platform. They manage a system-provided biometric authentication prompt, and provide a seamless experience by supporting various authentication types, including biometric ones such as fingerprint and face, as well as non-biometric types like PIN, password, and pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing the Perfect Splash for Android</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/implementing-the-perfect-splash-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/implementing-the-perfect-splash-for-android/</guid>
      <description>A Splash Screen is a screen which appears when you open an app on your mobile device. Sometimes it’s referred to as a launch screen or startup screen and shows up when your app is loading after you&amp;rsquo;ve just opened it.
When the loading is finished, you’ll be taken to a more functional screen where you can complete actions.
Splash screens appear on your screen for a fleeting moment – look away and you might miss them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE Simplified EP5 - Overcoming FOMO</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-ep5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-ep5/</guid>
      <description>We have already released 4 episodes of CSE Simplified to help you understand what CSE is all about and how to approach it. Many more episodes are yet to come. We hope they will help you get the most out of your B.Tech.
In this 5th episode, we want to talk about one of the most dangerous problem several students fall into. It&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;FOMO - Fear Of Missing Out&amp;rdquo;. Our aim is to clear out some points so that you can happily go through the journey of becoming a successful person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE Simplified EP4 - Choosing your laptop</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-ep4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-ep4/</guid>
      <description>Laptop plays a very crucial role in a CSE student&amp;rsquo;s life. Just after taking admission in the B.Tech CSE program, students are often in a hurry to buy a laptop. We have seen juniors making mistakes while buying a new laptop. They ask for help and people would just send a link for the sake of formality, without doing any research based on the requirements. Please beware of such things because you may regret such a decision in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE Simplified EP3 - CSE Subject Hierarchy</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-ep3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-ep3/</guid>
      <description>Namaskaram and welcome to the 3rd episode of the series CSE Simplified. The topic is - &amp;ldquo;B.Tech journey and Subject Hierarchy&amp;rdquo;. We will discuss the subjects that matter the most, the way you should approach them and how to avoid some common mistakes. We will show the subject hierarchy and the links between different subjects which might help you take the right decisions.
We have a lot of advice to give.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE Simplified EP2 - Which language should I learn? | Why learn C&#43;&#43; and Java?</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-ep2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-ep2/</guid>
      <description>Namaskaram friends!
There are a lot of programming languages to pick from. A CSE student often gets confused where to start. It is no smaller than a mystery when it comes to taking this decision.
So, here we are with yet another episode of our series CSE Simplified.
Following is the transcript of the episode. You may like to watch the video :
   
The purpose is to give you a big and clear perspective as to which language you should pick and why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE Simplified EP1 - The true CSE path</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-ep1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-ep1/</guid>
      <description>Namaskaram friends!
Welcome to the first episode of the series - CSE Simplified. In this episode, we will give you a brief overview of the true CSE path students should follow.
Following is the transcript of the episode. You may like to watch the video :
   
In this video series - CSE Simplified, we will be sharing our ideas and suggestions as to how a B.Tech CSE student should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE Simplified Trailer</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-trailer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/cse-simplified-trailer/</guid>
      <description>Namaskaram friends!
We hope you and your loved ones are safe in this unprecedented time we all are going through. Meanwhile, we are really excited to announce a new video series which you might find helpful.
This new video series is all about streamlining your B.Tech CSE journey. There are a lot of impactful decisions you need to take during these 4 years. It&amp;rsquo;s very important that you take such decisions free of greed or under bad influence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Apps</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/useful-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/useful-apps/</guid>
      <description>As you know there are lots of apps available in market but some Apps are Extraordinary and you should give them a chance.
Some Wonderful apps are not available on Playstore.
So I am going to give you Direct links of those Wonderful Apps.
Automate
Digi Locker
YouTube Vanced
Dcoder
Quoda
Solid Explorer
Calculator ++
Notion
Developer Assistant
Nova Launcher
Google Play Reward
QPython
Photomath
Shazam
Videoder
Universal Copy
To Do</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The reality of CSE in Private colleges of India</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/the-reality-of-cse-in-private-colleges-of-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/the-reality-of-cse-in-private-colleges-of-india/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The technical education system of CSE in private colleges is very bad. The colleges have opened just to run a business. They are not creating actual Computer Science Engineers. Majority of students end up getting placed in Service based jobs which stops their mental growth. These students do not get jobs CSE students deserve.
Now this problem has been prevailing since a long time now. Situation may have changed a bit but leaving it as is and hoping for better tomorrow will take a lot of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TC</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/tc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/tc/</guid>
      <description>TC is a full fledged e-Shopping app. We challenged ourselves to build an ecom system. The biggest challenge in the ecom system is to keep multiple apps (Admin &amp;amp; User) in sync.
 
Features Following are the major features of the Tirupati Collection app :
Browse sarees like a proUser can browse sarees by their Fabric &amp;amp; Type CatalagsBrowse sarees from a variety of catalogs Multiple images/portfolioView multiple images/portfolio for a single saree ZoomUser can zoom and view images/portfolio in full screen mode SearchSearch by saree, fabric, type &amp;amp; catalog Maintain profileSave profile for faster checkout Order managementEasily manage orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About us</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/about-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/about-us/</guid>
      <description>The Streamliners is a community of Problem Solvers.
We solve Real-World problems. We encourage how to solve. We guide, help, mentor how to solve.
Our motto - Deployment of skill or talent you have, in Real-life is important.
 
Lavish SwarnkarFounder &amp; CEO
A passionate programmer &amp; Android Developer
Deepak ChoudharyManaging Director &amp; Co-founder
Heart of the organization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact us</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSE Simplified</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/cse-simplified/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/cse-simplified/</guid>
      <description>CSE Simplified is a video series made for B.Tech CSE students. We have tried to cover all those topics that a CSE student is worried about. We have also cleared some misconceptions of students.
Watch now!
Trailer    
EP01 : The true CSE path    
EP02 : Which language should I learn? | Why learn C++ and Java?    
EP03 : CSE Subject Hierarchy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JU eezy Archive</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/ju-eezy-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/ju-eezy-archive/</guid>
      <description>JUFM (JU eezy v0.1) JU Food Menu
This version was not released globally. Work on JU eezy started in March 2018. Following build was completed in just 3 days.
Mess Food MenuThis was the feature to be implemented DrawerBack then, that&amp;#39;s how simple app was! Mess AdminMess Admin used to upload menu from here document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAAD Pricing Plan</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/android-training-pricing-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/android-training-pricing-plan/</guid>
      <description>High Standards Protect you from Low Quality Experiences. .blockquote-custom {position: relative;font-size: 1.1rem;margin-bottom: 50px;margin-top: 50px;}.blockquote-custom-icon {width: 50px;height: 50px;border-radius: 50%;display: flex;align-items: center;justify-content: center;position: absolute;top: -25px;left: 50px;} Only Videos won&amp;rsquo;t work We have seen people learning App Development through videos. And it&amp;rsquo;s terrible, they get stuck in between, no one to help, no one to give feedback and improve what they have built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android App Development (NAAD) Training</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/android-training-ext/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/android-training-ext/</guid>
      <description>We provide extensive training in Android. We guide, mentor and help students learn Android App development to solve Real-world problems.
 
Course structure  Recorded videos on YouTube (FREE) LIVE Doubts clearing sessions Handcrafted assignments Feedback &amp;amp; suggestions on Assignments Guidance &amp;amp; help in personal projects Team &amp;amp; opportunity to work on Real-world projects with the team  Duration : 4 - 8 weeks  APPLY NOW</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android App Development (NAAD) Training</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/android-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/android-training/</guid>
      <description>We provide extensive training in Android. We guide, mentor and help students become self-sustaining &amp;amp; self-employed Software Engineers (SWE).
 
Our definition of Software Engineer Our definition and qualification of Software Engineer is different. By making you a SWE, we do not mean to make you employable for SWE in FAANG. Instead we speak of it with a much broader perspective.
We believe CSE is meant to apply CS skills to solve real world problems by building solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Apps</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/other-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/other-apps/</guid>
      <description>Smart Podium   Smart Podium is an IOT based app used to control electrical appliances in the classroom.
  We developed this app during JU Rhythm Hackathon 2019.
  We WON the Hackathon.
  Along with the powerful backend &amp;amp; APIs, the app stood up because of its UI &amp;amp; animations. Have a look :
     Download the dummy app here and see the animations yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
