<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on The Streamliners</title>
    <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on The Streamliners</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:07:16 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indian Cyclists</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/indian-cyclists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 18:07:16 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/indian-cyclists/</guid>
      <description>Indian Cyclists 2020 helps cyclists and athlete to buy tickets for the participation in virtual events. With features like live leaderboard, completion certificates, online payments, sync physical activities at one place, etc. This app also helps organiser to run any event seamlessly and effectively.&#xA;Features Participate in different events Athletes can participate in differenct event by buying tickets with all types of online payment See leaderboard rankings See dynamic leaderboard of the participants based on their event types or categories Image based on events See different product images or riders images for the event Image based on events See different product images or riders images for the event Image based on events See different product images or riders images for the event Download certificates User can download their certificates with result after the event ends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daanpatra</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/daanpatra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 18:07:16 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/daanpatra/</guid>
      <description>Deliverable Developed a landing page where donor can enter personal info and make a donation. An admin panel is developed to export the donations&amp;rsquo; data.&#xA;Tech ReactJS, Kotlin, Kotlin Ktor, MongoDB, GCP, GCP App Engine, Razorpay</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouRide</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/you-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 18:07:16 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/you-ride/</guid>
      <description>Deliverable Developed an app where users can rent bikes on hourly, day and weekly basis. App facilitates in locking and unlocking booked bicycles via Bluetooth.&#xA;Tech Android, Kotlin, Jetpack Compose, Bluetooth</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PetStrong</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/pet-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:07:16 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/pet-strong/</guid>
      <description>Working as a tech consultant for PetStrong, we have built Pet Diet Food Calculator which calculates the daily calorie, water, fat, protein intake requirement of a given pet. Data is calculated based on the breed, breed size, age, weight, bcs score etc.&#xA;Currently, we are helping them build a robust Shopify Admin panel to cross communicate between two backends - Shopify &amp;amp; custom backend.&#xA;Tech ReactJS, Android, Serverside, Kotlin, Kotlin Ktor, MongoDB, GCP, GCP App Engine</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eChargeBays</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/echargebays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 18:07:16 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/echargebays/</guid>
      <description>Requirement eChargeBays works closely with EV manufacturers like Audi, Mercedes, BMW and EV Charger installtion service providers. Before the EV Charger is installed at EV owner&amp;rsquo;s residence, a survey has to happen which involves finding answer to questions like - personal / shared space, parking space available, electric meter configuration etc. Images and videos of that area are also required to be uploaded by the person conducting the survey. Earlier this survey process was manual - they used to fill physical printed forms, send images &amp;amp; videos on a WhatsApp group.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Riwaio</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/riwaio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 18:07:16 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/riwaio/</guid>
      <description>Deliverable Riwaio is a Porter like app where user can order packers &amp;amp; movers service on a wide range of vehicle choices. Target audience include wholesalers &amp;amp; suppliers who regularly supply their products on a loading vehicle. Users select the vehicle, type of material and enter the pickup, drop address. The platform consists of three apps - Delivery Partner, User &amp;amp; Admin.&#xA;One of the major challenge we faced at Riwaio was to notify the delivery partners of a new order in a low latency way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kin Social Media</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/kin-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 18:07:16 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/kin-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Deliverable Developed the complete chat feature from scratch using Sendbird SDK but with a custom UI. Handled complex features like double-sided pagination, media uploads, and future messages. Followed MVVM architecture and extensively used the Kotlin Standard Library&#xA;Tech Android, Kotlin, SendBird SDK, REST API, Kotlin Coroutines</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACI Worldwide</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/aci-worldwide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 18:07:16 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/aci-worldwide/</guid>
      <description>Deliverable A POS Android app that communicate with the underlying ACI&amp;rsquo;s eSocket.POS component via Socket programming. Messages are sent and received in XML format using the JAXB framework. Making JAXB compatible for Android was a major challenge.&#xA;Tech Android, Kotlin, Jetpack Compose, ApacheMina, Socket Programming, JAXB</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JU eezy</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/ju-eezy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 18:07:16 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/ju-eezy/</guid>
      <description>Problems solved Following are the features of the JU eezy app :&#xA;Homepage that looks promising Everyday help available at your fingertips Campus Guide View entire floor map of any building Search across the campus You can easily search indoor location of any classroom, lab, office etc. Search by Faculty&amp;#39;s name Get faculty cabin&amp;#39;s location by searching with faculty&amp;#39;s name Room description View alternate names, faculty details etc. for each room Filter map Narrow down floor map by selecting categories that matter to you Share indoor location Share any room location via unique links Notes Search from 100s of notes available of B.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LocatIN</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/locatin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/locatin/</guid>
      <description>What we do? We solve the problem of building fast, lightweight and easy to use indoor map solution for large infrastructures.&#xA;We are eagerly looking for customers. If you want your venue to be digitalized, contact us now! We will build a Unique NextGen Indoor map solution for your campus.&#xA;We are an incubated start-up @ JECRC Incubation center, JECRC University.&#xA;Videos Introductory video LocatIN for university Big Picture Our service To simplify indoor wayfindings at large campuses like hospitals, universities, shopping malls etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karobar Easy</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/karobar-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/karobar-easy/</guid>
      <description> Major features of the app </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Byaaz Book</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/byaaz-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/byaaz-book/</guid>
      <description>Major features of the app are : Interest Calculator You can calculate the interest in two different ways i.e. Simple Interest and Compound interest, based on your preference. Backup &amp;amp; Restore You can backup your whole data of customers and their transactions, with just one click. Byaaj Book gives you the flexibility to restore the whole content of the app. Fully Dynamic You can edit the customers, bills, and transactions, by long tapping on them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambika Parts</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/ambika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/ambika/</guid>
      <description>Ambika Parts consists of 2 apps, one for users and one for Admin.&#xA;User app Following are the major features of the user app :&#xA;Slideshow on Main page Using slideshow, admin can notiy his users of Main service or Information/Notice that he wants to deliver Shop Status &amp;amp; Timing Users can check whether the shop is closed or open and how much time is left to open/close Lottery System To increase user Engagement this app provides weekly Lottery Lottery System Users get notified of new lottery Coin system To increase sales, this app provides virtual coins on offline shopping which indeed gives prize Showcase Gallery This feature helps owner to show important items to their users Admin app Following is how the Admin Dashboard app looks like :</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VFresh</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/vfresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/vfresh/</guid>
      <description>Demo Following is a video walk-through of the VFresh eCom Platform :&#xA;You can try out the platform :&#xA;DOWNLOAD NOW You can request the Admin app access by contacting us. Admin app Features of Admin app :&#xA;Powerful Admin app provides all the powers in a single app Manage Categories Admin can organize item in categories. Categories are fully dynamic and can be edited anytime, anywhere. Sub categories Within a category, there can be any number of sub categories Product Management Admin can manage products within the app Add/Edit product Admin can add/edit products.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart Gaya</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/smart-gaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/smart-gaya/</guid>
      <description>This video shows how the app functions:&#xA;User app Following are the major features of the user app :&#xA;All service at your fingertips You can order any service you want, from salon, carpenter, AC Services, WiFi provider, Painters, Tutor, RO service, Plumber, CCTV, Driver, Accounts and many more Gaya Tour It helps users find cool and chilling Place from temples to bars. So one gets to know about most important places of Gaya General Store This is used by locals to Order General Store items according to their needs which gets delivered at their doorsteps at the EOD Drawer full of options In this app, hamburger icon provider you many useful options like Order History, Connect, Rate, Achievement etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food Bazaar</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/food-bazaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/food-bazaar/</guid>
      <description>Shopkeeper app Features of Shopkeeper app :&#xA;Dynamic Shopkeeper can edit menu, working hours, promocodes etc. anytime Order management Shopkeeper can manage orders and filter them by date User app Features of User app :&#xA;View nearby shops Shops are sorted based on their ratings Filter shops Filter shops based on city and type Categories User can view items by categories Cart Users can by items from one shop at a time Checkout App provides 2 delivery options.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blushed</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/blushed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/blushed/</guid>
      <description> This was a project we developed from scratch during an internship. The app UI has evolved after that. But still the core logic is written by us. The new app looks as follows.&#xA;Features Top Stories View the latest and popular stories on top Categries Browse through various categories Dark Mode Read in bed without hurting your eyes Filter Filter stories based on language you prefer Autoplay Messages can be shown in an hands-free autoplay mode Unique options panel From options, one can toggle sound effects, read description of story or delete progress Likes &amp;amp; Bookmarks Like &amp;amp; bookmark your favourite stories Guide The app helps you understand the UI/UX Track progress Easily see how much you&amp;#39;ve read Shimmer effect Beautiful Shimmer animation for loading data Swipe to remove Easily remove stories from Bookmarks, Likes by swiping </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TC</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/tc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 12:49:27 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/tc/</guid>
      <description>TC is a full fledged e-Shopping app. We challenged ourselves to build an ecom system. The biggest challenge in the ecom system is to keep multiple apps (Admin &amp;amp; User) in sync.&#xA;Features Following are the major features of the Tirupati Collection app :&#xA;Browse sarees like a pro User can browse sarees by their Fabric &amp;amp; Type Catalags Browse sarees from a variety of catalogs Multiple images/portfolio View multiple images/portfolio for a single saree Zoom User can zoom and view images/portfolio in full screen mode Search Search by saree, fabric, type &amp;amp; catalog Maintain profile Save profile for faster checkout Order management Easily manage orders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other Apps</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/other-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/portfolio/other-apps/</guid>
      <description>Smart Podium Smart Podium is an IOT based app used to control electrical appliances in the classroom.&#xA;We developed this app during JU Rhythm Hackathon 2019.&#xA;We WON the Hackathon.&#xA;Along with the powerful backend &amp;amp; APIs, the app stood up because of its UI &amp;amp; animations. Have a look :&#xA;Download the dummy app here and see the animations yourself. (Username/Password = q)&#xA;Watch a video illustrating how the app works here.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
