<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Firebase on The Streamliners</title>
    <link>https://thestreamliners.in/tags/firebase/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Firebase on The Streamliners</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thestreamliners.in/tags/firebase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notification Broadcast using BitVector</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/notification-broadcast-using-bitvector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/notification-broadcast-using-bitvector/</guid>
      <description>Namaskaram,
In this blog, I will be sharing an amazing story where I used BitVector &amp;amp; Bitwise operators to save myself from writing complex code &amp;amp; also using up a lot of Server Bandwidth.
The problem During my journey as an Android Developer, I came across a use case where I needed to send personalized notifications to my users.
This app was JU eezy, which I developed for our University. I had to send notifications to users based on their profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revoke role access using Firestore Security rules</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/revoke-role-access-using-firestore-security-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/revoke-role-access-using-firestore-security-rules/</guid>
      <description>Namaskaram,
Many applications require Role Based access. For example : in an e-commerce project, roles like Admin, Shopkeeper, Agent etc. may exist. Granting and revoking the access manually can be hard &amp;amp; inefficient.
In this blog, I am sharing an easy &amp;amp; efficient way to grant &amp;amp; revoke role based access in a Firebase app.
Naive approach   Let&amp;rsquo;s say : you have an Admin app where only authorised Admins should be able to login &amp;amp; access the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebase Log Events</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/firebase-log-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/firebase-log-events/</guid>
      <description>Firebase provides very powerful feature which is “Log Events”. The power of this feature is that you can check which feature of your app is used mostly by the users.
Let’s deep dive into the implementation (note that the complete implementation is in Java)
Add this library in your build.gradle file:
implementation &amp;#39;com.google.firebase:firebase-analytics&amp;#39; I had used firebase bom in my project so their is no need to give version to firebase-analytics library</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebase Push notifications using Admin SDK</title>
      <link>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/firebase-push-notifications-in-android-using-admin-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thestreamliners.in/blog/firebase-push-notifications-in-android-using-admin-sdk/</guid>
      <description>How to send push notifications through an Android app using firebase?  A notification is a message you can display to the user outside of your application’s normal UI. When you tell the system to issue a notification, it first appears as an icon in the notification area. Notifications are important to give timely updates to your android app users they require minimal UI to notify the user about the event.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
